

NISHANT NAGAR

GRAPHIC DESIGNER I SOCIAL MEDIA POST DESIGNER I 3D GRAPHIC ARTIST

ABOUT ME —

I am the one to look out for if you want to successfully manage Creative Graphic, Social Media Post Design and 3D Graphic Design projects; to work closely with customers, look at designs and meet continuous-time limits. Effective creation, promotion and direction of design and production teams. Ensure customized designs for clients by meeting their project requirements. Create and manage sales and marketing presentations. Extensive experience in multimedia, marketing and print design.

CONTACT —

+91 9510 85 99 33

nishantnagar95@gmail.com

Be behance.net/NishantNagar

in linkedin.com/in/nishant-nagar/

Ranip, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

ACHIEVEMENTS —

2023

Institute of Indian Interior DesignersBest Branding Team Award

2018

Professional Certification

3Ds Max Autodesk

2017

Endeavor Careers Pvt. Ltd.Best Branding Team Award

2017

Professional Certification AutoCAD Autodesk

EDUCATION —

2010 - 2013

Arena Animation Academy Specialist Programmer

Arena Animation Multimedia

2008 - 2011

Bachelor of Commerce

Gujarat University

WORK EXPERIENCE —

2022 - Till Date

AimCorp

Art Direction, Visualizer Designer, Event Designing, Branding & Identity Marketing, Lead - Creative Design, Social Media Post Designer, Trade Show Exhibitor, Event Production

Senior Manager

Responsible for all the graphic design and visual output on all brand briefs. Working closely with the creative and operations teams to translate ideas and concepts into design. Staying up to date with the latest design trends in on-ground events, music festivals and concert experiences. Actively contributing design solutions to pitch presentations. Creating visual elements such as logos, illustrations, event identities, stage designs, event collaterals like posters, invitations, branding, e-mailers, print campaigns, advertisements, brochures and many other forms of visual communication etc. Ensuring designs are print ready and adhere to print and brand guidelines at all times. Producing cutting-edge and creative designs for brochures, posters, signage, displays, flyers, print advertisements, infographics, and email campaigns. Collaborating with Senior Manager - Corporate Communications, Lead - Creative Design and Lead - Content Services to plan and design effective print and digital marketing campaigns.

2021 - 2022

Freelance

Creative Graphic Designer and Social Media Post Designer

Freelance Graphic Designer and Social Media Post Designer

Create graphic designs for web communications and marketing materials. Work with management to understand specific brand usage principles in graphic designs. Create high-quality images for newsletters, business articles and blogs. Develop effective imagery concepts for ad creation. Create templates for business and promotional materials. Support new and ongoing ad campaigns by developing postcards and ad materials.

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED) —

2020 - 2021

Miceideas

Flyer and OBS Designer

2015 - 2020

Endeavor Careers Pvt. Ltd. (HO)

Creative Graphic Designer and Social Media Infographics Designer

2014 - 2015

AUM Event & Promotions

Creative Graphic Designer, 3D Exhibition Stall and Theme Graphics Design, Video Editing and Photography

2011 - 2014

Goplee Advertising & Marketing

Creative Graphic Designer and 3D Graphics Designer Artist

2010 - 2011

Dynamic Methods

Graphic and Web Designer

Sr. Graphic Designer

My profile included visualizations of the clients' needs and also correcting them for their good. I was in charge of all kinds of flyer design and OBS Design Branding and Solutions for the clients, including Events and Conference. Designed company logos, flyers, brochures for various types of organizations in a variety of Healthcare industries based online of work, corporate personality, and client preferences. Manage projects from start to finish including the planning, conceptualizing, creating detailed coordinating with the production team.

Assistant Manager

Directly responsible for the overall design and Illustrative, Graphic, Visuals for use in social media, indoor-outdoor exhibition display and advertising collateral. Communicates directly with Design, Branding, Marketing and Academic Teams on a regular basis. Support product management and development in all issues regarding the realization of graphic solutions. Work with online team to develop email marketing and banner ad, Work closely with Creative Services Project Manager to track and maintain Trim Approval Forms Stay up-to-date with design trends and competitors within the industry. knowledge of digital media requirements for social Media platforms. Ensure that designs meet corporate and client expectations are within budget and deadlines are met. Be an active participant in brainstorming sessions, planning, and design and department meetings.

Visualizer Creative Graphics and 3D Graphics Artist

3D elements and collateral, and product displays; projects from start to finish including the planning, conceptualizing, creating detailed drawings, coordinating with the production team or managing production directly, managing vendors. Visualizes and illustrates event designs from conceptual mood board to the final output, as well as detailing the event narrative in a storyboard format (or similar). Communicate project status, timelines and delivery information to clients and internal teams. Experience with building and maintaining client relationships in a team-based government or professional services environment.

Visualizer Graphics Designer and 3D Graphics Artist

Prominent clients handled by me were Godrej, ONGC and many other private and govt clients. My profile included visualizations of the clients' needs and also correcting them for their good. I was in charge of all kinds of Branding and Advertising solutions for the clients, including Events and Exhibition (Government 3D stall Design). Designed company logos for various types of organizations in a variety of industries based online of work, corporate personality, and client preferences. Manage projects from start to finish including the planning, conceptualizing, creating detailed drawings, coordinating with the production team or managing production directly, managing vendors and 3D renderers.

Junior Graphic and Web Designer

Assisting in the conception, and execution of visual design across web, mobile, tablets, and print. Implements user-centered/focused designs and processes to identify specific user needs and find the best solutions. Conducted, planned, and synthesized user research for the use of app development team.

EXPERTISE —

- Newspaper ads, Magazine, Posters, Banners, Billboards
- Brochures (print and digital)
- Branding and Typography
- Social Media Post Design
- Concept / Creative Design
- 3D Exhibitions Stall Designa and Theme Design Trade Show Displays Design

STRENGTHS —

- Creativity
- Communication
- Time-Management
- Teamwork
- Research
- Leadership
- Desire to learn
- Brainstorming

SKILLS —

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- CorelDRAW
- · Hand Sketching
- Print Design
- Infographic Design

3D Software

• Autodesk 3Ds Max

PERSONAL INFO -

- Date of Birth: 25th Oct 1987
- Marital Status: Single
- Gender: Male
- Nationality: Indian
- Religion: Hindu

LANGUAGES

English	~	~	~
Hindi	~	~	~
Gujarat	~	~	~

HOBBIES

- Photography
- Traveling
- Drawing
- Listening music
- Gaming